{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which one of the following questions is relevant to the construction estimates :", "opta": "Did the estimators precisely evaluate site conditions ?", "optb": "Did the estimators use short cut methods which may be un realistic in their situation ?", "optc": "How much money will the contractor's risk, loosing if he Were to submit bid on the raw estimate of cost.", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ratio obtained by dividing 'quick assests' by current liabilities is called", "opta": "Turnover ratio", "optb": "Acid test ratio", "optc": "Solvency ratio", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following definitions, is correct ?", "opta": "The ratio of total debt to share holder's equity is called 'debt ratio'.", "optb": "The ratio debt-to-total assests is called Debt-to-total assest ratio.", "optc": "The ratio of earnings before interest and taxes for a particular reporting period to the amount of interest charges for the period, is called interest coverage ratio.", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the element of the cost from the following:", "opta": "direct material", "optb": "direct labour", "optc": "Over head", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The estimator for definitive estimates must be able :", "opta": "and an all-around construction expert.", "optb": "to read the plans and specifications to determine accurate quantities of permanent materials and installed Equipment.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The change in the amount of money over a given time period is called 'time value' of money, a most important concept in engineering economy.", "optb": "The manifestation of the time value of money is termed as interest.", "optc": "Interest on borrowing = present amount owed - original loan", "optd": "The original investment (or loan) is referred to as principal.", "opte": "All of these.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is included in financial ratios of the firm ?", "opta": "Profitability ratio", "optb": "Liquidity ratio", "optc": "Turnover ratio", "optd": "Ratio of overall performances", "opte": "All of these", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The financial ratio summarises some aspect of the firm's financial condition at the time of preparing a balance sheet.", "optb": "Both the numerator and denominator of financial ratios come directly from the balance sheet.", "optc": "Income statement ratios compare one 'flow' item from the income statement to another flow item from the income statement.", "optd": "Income statement ratios compare a flow item from the income statement to another flow item form the income statement", "opte": "All of these", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Refer to the cash flow diagram of uniform gradient in a cash flow (in the given figure), the gradient is :", "opta": "Rs 10000 per year", "optb": "Rs 15000 per year", "optc": "Rs 20000 per year", "optd": "Rs 25000 per year", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the cash-flow diagram shown in the given figure", "opta": "Equal deposits of Rs 3000 per year (A) are made, starting now.", "optb": "The rate of interest is 10% per yearaccount", "optc": "The amount accumulated after the seventh deposit is to be computed", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The estimate based on a detailed quantity survey and furnishes the most accurate and reliable estimate possible is known as", "opta": "Conceptual estimate", "optb": "Definitive estimate", "optc": "Probabilistic estimate", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sunk costs include :", "opta": "a past expenditure", "optb": "an unrecovered balance", "optc": "an invested capital that cannot be retreived", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current assests less inventories divided by current liabilities is known as", "opta": "Liquidity ratio", "optb": "Current ratio", "optc": "Acid-Test (or Quick) ratio", "optd": "Debts ratio", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following statements is correct?", "opta": "The number of years required to recover the initial cash investment in a project, is called Pay Back period (PBP).", "optb": "The discount rate that equates the present value of the expected Net Cash Flows (CFs) with the Initial Cash Outflow (ICO) is known as internal rate of return.", "optc": "The present value of the proposal's net cash flows, less the proposal's initial cash outflow is known as the Net Present Value (NPV)", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The alternatives which are standalone solutions for given situations in engineering involve :", "opta": "a purchase cost (first cost)", "optb": "the anticipated life of the assest", "optc": "the yearly costs of maintaining the assest (annual maintenance and operating cost)", "optd": "the anticipated resaleable value (salvage value) and the interest return (rate of return)", "opte": "All of these", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ratio of current assests to current liabilities is known as", "opta": "Liquidity ratio", "optb": "Current ratio", "optc": "Acid-Test (or Quick) ratio", "optd": "Debts ratio", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "An annuity is a series of equal payments occurring at equal period of time.", "optb": "Annuity is called an equal payment or uniform payment series.", "optc": "An annuity may have periods of time of any length but should always be of equal length.", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The construction estimate of a project is used by :", "opta": "the owner of the facility", "optb": "the consulting architect/engineer", "optc": "the contractor of the project", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Both architect and engineer make use of the cost estimate of the project:", "opta": "for site selection", "optb": "for designing of the project", "optc": "for choosing alternatives", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a is the base amount expenditure, b is the increase in the operation cost each year over a period of n years, the total cost of maintenance is :", "opta": "a + (n + 1) b", "optb": "a + (n - 1) b", "optc": "a x (n - 1) b", "optd": "a - (n - 1) b", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The more critical (or severe) test of the firm's liquidity can be judged by :", "opta": "Liquidity ratio", "optb": "Current ratio", "optc": "Acid-Test (or Quick) ratio", "optd": "Debts ratio", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ratio analysis of a construction firm is used for analysis by :", "opta": "share holders", "optb": "firm's management", "optc": "Banks of the firm", "optd": "financial analysts", "opte": "All of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "", "optb": "Over head cost per unit = Overhead ratio x direct labour cost/unit", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "neither (a) nor (6)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Probabilistic estimating of a construction project includes:", "opta": "Labour", "optb": "Productivity", "optc": "wage scale", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A construction estimate is used", "opta": "to judge tentatively or approximate value of the project", "optb": "to produce a statement of the approximate cost", "optc": "to decide an approximation of the value of the project and not the exact cost.", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The capital required to get a project started, is called first cost.", "optb": "The costs associated with a new or existing project that remain unaffected by the changes in activity level over the normal range of operation of the project, are called fixed costs.", "optc": "The group of costs that vary proportionately to the changes in the activity level of a new or existing project are called variable costs.", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Present worth Annuity (PWA) is generally known as", "opta": "Premium annuities", "optb": "Income annuities", "optc": "Future annuities", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the ratio which gives us sufficient information by which to judge the financial condition and performance of the firm, from the following:", "opta": "Liquidity ratio", "optb": "Financial leverage ratio", "optc": "Activity ratio", "optd": "Portability", "opte": "None of these", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The ratios which show profitability in relation to sales and those which show profitability in relation to investment, are called profitability ratios.", "optb": "The ratio of gross profit and net sales, is called profitability in relation to sales ratio.", "optc": "The ratio of net profit after taxes to total assests is known as profitability in relation to investment ratio", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The financial analysis helps to judge:", "opta": "The operational efficiency of the firm", "optb": "The financial position of the firm.", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Neither (a) nor (b)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If interest is paid more than once in a year, i is the rate of interest per year, n is the number of periods in years and m is a number of periods per years, compound amount factor (CAF) is :", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a cash flow series :", "opta": "uniform gradient signifies that an income or disbursement changes by the same amount in each interest period.", "optb": "Either an increase or a decrease in the amount of a cash flow is called the gradient.", "optc": "The gradient in the cash flow may be positive or negative.", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If P is principal amount, i is the rate of interest and n is the number of periods in years, then the interest factor is :", "opta": "(1 + ni)", "optb": "(ni - 1)", "optc": "ni", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "Ratio analysis is the procedure of determining and interpreting numerical relationship of various items of the financial statement.", "optb": "All financial ratios are obtained by relating two sets of information contained in a Single financial statement.", "optc": "The relationship between two accounting figures expressed mathematically, is known as a financial ratio.", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The ability of a company to meet obligations which are likely to mature in short term, is called liquidity.", "optb": "The liquidity ratio may be defined as a relationship of current liabilities and current assests and advances.", "optc": "The liquidity ratios are used to indicate the financial position of the firm.", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The capital Recovery Factor (equal payments) of Capital Recovery Annuity is :", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current ratio is :", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The interest calculated on the basis of 365 days a year, is known as :", "opta": "interest", "optb": "ordinary simple interest", "optc": "exact simple interest", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If S is the future capital accumulated in n years at the rate of interest i per annum, then present worth is :", "opta": "", "optb": "S(1 + i)n", "optc": "S(1 + i)1/n", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a cash-flow diagram :", "opta": "Time 0 is considered to be the present", "optb": "Time 1 is considered to be the end of time period 1", "optc": "A vertical arrow pointing up indicates a positive cash flow", "optd": "An arrow pointing downward indicates a negative cash flow", "opte": "All of these", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Each financial ratio is generally compared by", "opta": "a past ratio calculated from the past financial standard of the firm.", "optb": "a ratio developed by using the projected financial statement of the firm.", "optc": "a ratio of some selected firms most progressive and successful at the point of consideration.", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The key to profitable operation for project cost control, is :", "opta": "To keep the project cost equal to original cost estimate.", "optb": "To keep the project cost equal to subsequent construction budget.", "optc": "To keep the project cost within the cost budget and knowing when and where job costs are deviating.", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The annuity which refers to a debt payment for recovering the initial amount or capital in equal periodical payments, is known as;", "opta": "Present Worth Annuity", "optb": "Sinking fund annuity", "optc": "Compound annuity", "optd": "Capital recovery annuity", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The product of CAF (S P) and PWF (S P) is:", "opta": "1/2", "optb": "1", "optc": "1/3", "optd": "1/4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct reason for making conceptual (or preliminary) estimate from the following:", "opta": "To have a check on a definitive cost estimate.", "optb": "To check qoutations from contractors and/or sub contractors.", "optc": "To compute target estimate for the owner while drawings and specifications are in initial stage.", "optd": "All of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "A NPV profile graph shows the curvilinear relationship between the net present value of the project and discount rate employed.", "optb": "In a NPV profile, if discount rate is zero, then net present value is simply total cash inflows less the total cash outflows of the project.", "optc": "As the discount rate increases, the net present value profile slopes downward to the right.", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The project contractor relies on the cost of the estimate :", "opta": "for submission of a competitive bid for a lumpsum contract", "optb": "for a unit price contract", "optc": "for preparation of a definitive estimate to help negotiate contract.", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The wages of supervisors and material handlers are charged as :", "opta": "Over head", "optb": "direct labour cost", "optc": "indirect labour cost", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The CRF (ep) is also known as: [CRF(EP) - 8% - 7], where", "opta": "8% is the rate of interest per year", "optb": "money is borrowed for n = 7 years", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Neither (a) nor (b)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Annuities involve:", "opta": "a series of payments", "optb": "all payments of equal amount", "optc": "payment at equal time intervals", "optd": "payments at the end of periods.", "opte": "All of these", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}